大家好。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Hi everyone.
很高兴你们今天能来到这里。
Super excited for
you all to be here today.
我们将学习中级
And we're gonna be learning
about intermediate, and
然后在小括号里加上了今天先进的盖茨比。
then in tiny parenthetical slash,
advanced Gatsby today.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 我们将进入一些边缘
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: We're gonna get
into some of the kinda edges and
你可以对盖茨比做些什么。
corners of what you can do with Gatsby.
进入一些更强大的东西,
Get into some more powerful stuff,
移动到你通常认为一组网站能够做到的范围之外。
moving outside of what you would typically
think a set of site is capable of.
我真的很期待这样做。
And I'm really really
looking forward to doing it.
关于我，我是杰森。
So, a little bit about me I'm Jason.
我是一个，我已经把学习作为我的职业，我真的很喜欢这样做。
I am kind of a, I've made it my career to
learn, I really really like doing that.
我学习的方式之一就是教书，所以我尽可能经常这样做,
And one of the ways I learn is by
teaching, so I do that as often as I can,
这也是我今天来这里的部分原因。
which is part of the reason
why I'm here today.
我目前是 Netlify 的首席开发人员体验工程师。
I'm currently a principal developer
experience engineer at Netlify.
在此之前，我是盖茨比的开发者关系部门的负责人
Prior that I was head of
Developer Relations at Gatsby and
在那之前，我是 IBM 的前端架构师。
then I was a front end
architect at IBM before that.
我住在俄勒冈州的波特兰市，也是一名教师
I live in Portland,
Oregon and also I teach a or
我每周都在现场直播特维奇。
I run a weekly live stream on Twitch.
每周有几次我和某人一起编程
A couple of times a week I
pair program with somebody and
我们白手起家。
we build something from scratch.
它叫做“和杰森一起学习” ，非常有趣。
It's called Learn with Jason,
it's a lot of fun.
它充满了愚蠢的声音效果，你可以随时聊天,
And it's full of silly sound
effects you can chat along live,
如果你想学点什么，这是个好机会
it's a good time if you wanna
learn something and and
也希望我那些糟糕的笑话能让你笑一笑。
also hopefully giggle a little
bit at my terrible jokes.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 在我们开始之前，我想先说明一下是谁
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: So, before we get
started I wanna set a little bit of who
这个研讨会只是为了确保我们的假设是正确的。
this workshop is for just to make sure
that we've got our assumptions straight.
我有两个假设。
I'm gonna make two assumptions.
一是你以前至少建过一个简单的盖茨比遗址,
One is that you've built at least
a simple Gatsby site before,
我们将会讨论很多盖茨比的内部细节。
we're gonna be talking about
a lot of the internals of Gatsby.
我也不会再重复那些文件的名字,
And I'm not gonna go over things
like what the files are named,
或诸如此类的事情。
or those sorts of things.
所以，一定要问我是否做了一些你不清楚的事情。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: So, definitely ask if
I do something that you're not clear on.
但我假设你至少
But I will be assuming
that you've at least
我以前见过一些盖茨比的发展过程。
seen some of the Gatsby
development process before.
而且我还假设你们至少对“反应”有点熟悉。
And I'll also be assuming that you're
at least a little familiar with React.
所以我们要做一些事情，比如使用反应钩。
So we're going to be doing
things like using React Hooks.
我们今天要管理国家和处理表格。
We're going to be managing state today and
handling forms.
所以，如果你从来没有使用过反应或者你对反应感到不舒服,
So, if you've never used React or
you're not super comfortable with React,
你可能想回去看 Brian Holt 的《反应简介》或者
you may want to go back and
watch Brian Holt's Intro to React or
另一个课程可以帮助你加快速度。
another course that'll kind of
bring you up to speed on that.
如果你对盖茨比感到不舒服，那么你可能想回去
If you're uncomfortable with Gatsby,
then you may want to go back and
观看我的前端大师课程，有点像初学者盖茨比。
watch my front end Masters course
on kind of a Beginner Gatsby.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 话虽如此，我认为我们已经准备好加入了。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: With that being said,
I think we're ready to jump in.
所以在我们讨论盖茨比之前,
So before we talk about what Gatsby is,
了解它所解决的问题是很重要的。
it's kind of important to understand
what the problems are that it's solving.
所以第一件事就是对现代社会的挑战做一个概述
So the first thing is just to kind of get
an overview of the challenges of modern
网页开发。
web development.
我看到的最大的问题，特别是最近,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: The biggest problem
that I've seen, especially lately,
在现代网络开发中的起步是非常艰难的。
is that getting started in modern web
development is really overwhelming.
有很多选择，有很多很多件。
There are tons of options,
there are lots and lots of pieces.
而且他们也不一定清楚他们是如何组合在一起的。
And they don't necessarily feel
clear as to how they fit together.
感觉好像发生了很多事情。
It feels like a lot of stuff going on.
这个生态系统非常嘈杂，每个人都说他们
It's very noisy in the ecosystem with
everybody saying that they've got
偏好和那些偏好通常是像事实一样陈述的
preferences and those preferences
are usually stated like facts so
很难理解什么是最佳实践。
it can be really difficult to understand
what the quote unquote best practices are.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 最重要的是，我们管理数据的方式在不断发展。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: On top of that
the way we manage data is evolving.
我的意思是，过去是这样，至少在我刚开始的时候是这样
I mean, it used to be, back in the day,
at least when I was getting started that
你会有某种集中存储的数据。
you'd have some kind of
a centralized store of your data.
你会有一个 API 或者你会有你的 WordPress 实例或者
You would have an API or
you would have your WordPress instance or
你的 Drupal 实例。
your Drupal instance.
这样就可以解决一切问题了。
And that would manage everything.
如果你在 WordPress 中有一个博客。
If you had a blog that was in WordPress.
如果你有电子商务，那是在 WordPress 中。
If you had e-commerce,
that was in WordPress.
如果你有一个表单，那就是在 WordPress 中。
If you had a form, that was in WordPress.
所以你们的 CMS 就像是一个整体,
And so
your CMS was kind of this monolithic,
一刀切的数据管理方法。
one size fits all approach
to data management.
现在这种情况正在改变，所以它开始分崩离析。
And that's changing now so
it's starting to come apart.
我们一会儿再谈这个问题。
We'll talk a little bit more
about that in a minute.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 然后把它做对是很困难的。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: And
then just getting it right is hard.
现代网络开发的任何一个特定的细节都可能成为年和年的职业
Any particular tiny sliver of modern web
development could become a career in and
我们看到了这种情况的发生。
of itself, and we're seeing that happen.
像哈利 · 罗宾逊这样的人就是通过优化网络来完成他的整个职业生涯的
People like Harry Robinson have made an
entire career just out of optimizing web
性能。
performance.
而其他人，比如瑞秋 · 安德鲁,
And other people, like Rachel Andrew,
在教授 CSS 和 CSS Grid 方面取得了一定的成就。
have made a career out of
teaching people CSS and CSS Grid.
你可以在这些东西中的任何一个进入兔子洞，这是一个完全
You can go down the rabbit hole in any
one of these things and it's a completely
有效的职业，需要获得和分享大量的知识。
valid profession with a huge amount
of knowledge to acquire and share.
所以对于我们这些在公司工作的普通开发人员来说,
So for us, the average
developer working in a company,
我们怎么才能把这些事情都做对呢？
how do we expect to get
all of these things right?
我们怎样才能不仅建立一个好的应用程序
How do we expect to not
only build a good app and
提供良好的功能，但性能是否正确？
deliver good features,
but get performance right?
可维护性是否正确？
Get maintainability right?
确保我们运送的是现代化的应用程序和我们一起扩展,
Make sure that we're shipping modern and
apps that are gonna scale with us,
有太多不同的事情需要我们去了解
and there are just so many different
things that we need to know in
为了做好这件事，这是超级无法抗拒的。
order to get this right and
that's super overwhelming.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 《了不起的盖茨比》试图解决其中的一些问题
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: So Gatsby is
an attempt to address some of these
其中一种思考方式就是这是条捷径，对吗？
challenges and one of the ways to think
about it is that it's a shortcut, right?
因此，《了不起的盖茨比》是开发人员快速开发优秀应用程序的捷径
So Gatsby is a shortcut to allow
developers to quickly build excellent apps
和网站。
and sites.
这意味着它试图设置一些默认值
And what that means is that it's
trying to set some defaults and
一些途径，这样你不得不做出更少的决定，以获得一个好的结果。
some pathways so that you have to make
fewer decisions to get a good outcome.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 为了说明这意味着什么,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: So to give
an illustration of what that means,
许多工作流程需要大量的样板文件才能开始，而且
a lot of workflows involve a ton
of boilerplate to get started, and
我们来举例说明一下。
let's just illustrate that.
假设我有，我想写一些代码
So let's say I've got,
I wanna write some code and
我想把密码传到网上，对吧？
I wanna get that code on to the internet,
right?
那看起来像是一步到位的事情但是当你开始深入研究的时候,
That's, that seems like a one step thing,
but when you start to dig into it,
如果你要从头开始，开始你自己的事业，你最终会。
if you're going from scratch and rolling
your own thing, you're gonna end up.
好的，我需要建立一些网络包，我想使用现代的功能。
Okay, I need to set up some web packs,
I wanna use modern features.
好吧，这意味着我必须拥有巴别塔，因为我需要透露这些特征
Okay, well that means I have to have Babel
because I need to transpile those features
变成浏览器能理解的东西。
into something that
the browser understands.
然后你需要张贴 CSS，这样你就可以使用现代的 CSS 特性。
Then you need post CSS so
that you can use modern CSS features.
现在你看到的是 node so
Now you're looking at node so
你可以在某个地方建立一个服务器来承载这些代码。
that you can actually set up a server
that hosts that code somewhere.
然后你可能会进入像库伯内特斯这样的集装箱。
Then you might be getting into
containers like Kubernetes.
然后 NginX，如果你想设置反向代理，因为你的容器
Then NginX if you want to set up
reverse proxies because your containers
管理应用程序的不同部分。
are managing different parts of the app.
您需要一个 CDN 像快速，以便您可以得到您的用户的东西快速。
You need a CDN like fastly so that you
can get things to your users quickly.
如果你感到不知所措，我的意思是，这是压倒性的。
And if you're feeling overwhelmed,
I mean, this is overwhelming.
这些事情中的每一件都可以成为一种职业，对吗？
Each one of these things
could be a career, right?
我的意思是，当我在 IBM 工作的时候，有些人的整个工作
I mean, there were people when I
worked at IBM whose entire job
只是在处理集装箱。
was just dealing with the containers.
反向代理让他们在我们部署的服务上保持活力。
And the reverse proxies that kept them
alive on the services that we deployed.
因此，有大量的复杂因素会随着你的介绍而出现
So there are a huge number of
complexities that get introduced as you
开始在现代网络应用程序上运行。
start to work on modern web apps.
所以，为了简化盖茨比所采取的方法，让我们来看看
So to simplify that Gatsby kind of
takes an approach of let's take all of
这些东西。
these things.
只要设置一些快乐的默认路径，就可以为绝大多数网站设置这样的路径
And just set up some happy path defaults
and say that for the vast majority of web
应用程序有一种方法来运输这些，将大多数时候是正确的。
apps there's a way to ship these that
will be mostly right most of the time.
这样我们就可以去掉大量的样板文件。
And that allows us to remove
a ton of boilerplate.
因此，我们可以开始并部署一些东西到生产中，这将开始
So we can get started and deploy something
to production that will start out
通过了所有灯塔的绩效审核。
passing all the lighthouse audits for
performance.
它将开始得到全 a 的网页测试。
It'll start out getting
straight A's on web page test.
作为一个网页开发者，你不必成为一个专家,
And that puts you, as a web developer in a
position to not have to become an expert,
但是要注意你在做什么，确保你没有
but just to pay attention to what you're
doing to make sure that you're not having
回归。
regressions.
所以一般的网络应用，如果你开始添加一些东西
So the average web app,
if you start you add something and
那你就得想想为什么这么慢。
then you have to go
figure out why it's slow.
这故意采取了大量的样板，并说，如果你做它喜欢
This intentionally takes a lot of
the boilerplate and says if you do it like
这个，你会没事的，然后当你开始添加东西的时候
this, you're gonna be okay and then as you
start to add things you just have to be
而不是提出所有的样板文件。
watching as opposed to kind of bringing
up the whole boilerplate just enough.
它看起来有点像这样，你有了你的代码，你在《了不起的盖茨比》里写了这个代码
And it looks kind of like this, you have
your code, you write that in Gatsby and
你把它推到 Netlify，然后连接到 Github 和
you push it up to Netlify
which hooks up to Github and
把它放在互联网上，所以这是一个更简单的过程。
that puts it on the Internet,
so it's a much simpler process.
在盖茨比工作流中，你使用 React 和 GraphQL。
And inside that Gatsby workflow,
you're using React and GraphQL.
所以你不需要编排那么多的工具,
So you're not doing quite as
much orchestration of tools,
你做的更多的是你真正想做的事情。
you're doing more building the actual
thing that you want to work on.
因此，这需要花费大量的工作，让你集中精力
And so it takes a lot of that work out
of the way and allows you to focus on
航运功能，而不是建立航运功能的基础。
shipping features, as opposed to setting
up the foundation for shipping features.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 另一种看待盖茨比的方式是，它是一种编曲
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Another way to think
about Gatsby is that it's an orchestration
图层用于驯服内容网格。
layer for taming the Content Mesh.
内容网格是盖茨比编造的一个时髦词汇
The Content Mesh is a buzzword
that Gatsby made up but
我喜欢它是因为它描述了
Iove it because it kind of
describes what's happening in
前端的景观现在，如果你看看单片 CMS
the the front end landscape right now,
if you look at monolithic CMS
他们都开始放弃我们能处理一切的想法。
is they're all starting to back away from
this idea that we can handle everything.
有一个无头的实现，Drupal 称之为
WordPress has a headless implementation,
Drupal calls it
分离的 Drupal，它不再有关于前端的意见。
decoupled Drupal where it no longer
has opinions about the front end.
大多数主要的服务都开始通过 API 发布他们的数据
Most major services are starting to
ship all of their data via API so
你可以在上面建造自己的前端。
that you can build your own
front end on top of it.
这意味着我们正在远离一刀切或者
That means that we're moving away from
this idea of one size fits all or
一个统治他们的工具。
one tool to rule them all.
我们正开始朝着内容网格的想法前进。
And we're starting to move toward
this idea of the Content Mesh.
你可以把不同的服务整合在一起，使用它们来做它们最擅长的事情。
Where you pull different services together
to use them for what they're best at.
一个思考这个问题的方法是，如果你看一个普通的网站,
A way to think about this is,
if you look at the average website,
你有你的图片，你有你的搜索功能，你有内容。
you've got your images, you've got your
search functionality, you've got content.
也许你有你卖的产品。
Maybe you've got products that you sell.
这些东西都会从不同的服务中提取出来。
And each of those things is going to
be pulled from a different service.
所以也许你的图像就在你附近的云端。
So maybe you've got your
images on cloud near you.
也许你正在使用 Algolia 进行搜索，Contentful 管理你的内容,
Maybe you're using Algolia for search,
Contentful to manage your content,
管理你的电子商务。
Stripe to manage your e-commerce.
这是一件好事。
And that's a good thing.
也就是说你使用的这些工具,
That means that you're using
each of these tools which,
这取决于你问的是班上最好的学生。
depending on who you ask is
best in class at what it does.
你使用它只是为了它能做什么。
And you're using it only for what it does.
你并不是想把 Contentful 变成一个电子商务平台。
You're not trying to make Contentful
into an e-commerce platform.
它不是用来干这个的。
That's not what it's for.
你不是要把 Stripe 变成一个内容管理系统,
You're not trying to make Stripe
into a content management system,
因为那不是用来干这个的。
because that's not what that's for.
你只是使用他们最擅长的工具，而且
You just use the tools for
what they're best at, and
把它们缝在你的前端。
stitch them together in your front end.
现在，你可以想象，这可能会变得有点复杂，因为我们现在正在讨论
Now, as you can imagine, this can get kind
of complicated because now we're talking
在这个简单的例子中，我们看到了四个不同的 api
about just in this simple example we're
looking four different APIs that we have
要求的东西，把东西放在一起，坚持到网页和
to request things from, put together,
stick on to the page and
确保我们没有把一切都搞得太慢。
make sure that we didn't make everything
horribly slow in the process.
所以盖茨比所做的就是集中式的 GraphQL 层。
So what Gatsby does is it has this
idea of a centralized GraphQL layer.
它会从你能想到的任何来源获取数据
And it will pull data from any
source that you can think of
无论是文件系统，软件即服务，还是 API,
whether that's a file system,
software as a service and API,
类似的东西，把它拉进来，放到集中的 GraphQL 层中。
something like that, pull it in and
put it into the centralized GraphQL layer.
然后在 React 中查询 GraphQL 层。
Then you query that
GraphQL layer in React.
这就意味着
And that means that for
开发人员的数据访问保持不变，无论您使用的是什么来源。
developers data access stays the same
no matter what source you're using.
您将需要一个 GraphQL API，并且它开始让您感到熟悉
You're going to be requiring a GraphQL
API, and it starts to feel familiar as you
对盖茨比导入数据的方式越来越满意,
get more and more comfortable with
the way the Gatsby imports data,
所以一切都开始变得一样了。
so everything starts to
feel about the same.
你总是会得到所有满意的数据和节点,
You're always gonna get all
Contentful data, and the nodes,
然后你会在里面找到一些磁场。
and then you'll get some fields inside.
这一点在所有服务中都是正确的。
And that stays true across services.
一旦你做到了一旦你让一切运转起来,
Once you've done,
once you've got everything working,
构建它并输出一个装满静态资产的文件夹。
you build it and that outputs
a folder full of static assets.
静态资产可以上传到 Amazon S3 bucket 中以取消
The static assets can be uploaded
to an Amazon S3 bucket to nullify
任何 CDN 类型的对象存储，你想，这是伟大的，因为
to whatever CDN kind of object storage
that you want, which is great because
这意味着你不必保持一个活着的运行服务器，你只需要 CDN。
that means you don't have to keep a live
running server, you just need the CDN.
至于保持东西的价格和便宜，一个 CDN 大约是
And as far as keeping things up and
inexpensive, a CDN is about
最好的方法就是保持东西的可用性，而不是花一大笔钱。
the best way to keep things available and
not spend a fortune doing it.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 然后当它进入浏览器时，它就会重新水合成一个 React 应用程序。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: And then when it hits
the browser rehydrates into a React app.
这意味着你不会失去任何动态功能，你仍然可以
And that means that you don't lose any
dynamic capabilities, you can still make
异步请求，你仍然可以做客户端路由，你仍然可以
asynchronous requests, you can still
do client side routing, you can still
你可以使用 React 应用程序做所有的事情。
do authentication, all the things that
you would do with the regular React app.
但是你已经省去了很多把 React 应用放到网上的复杂性。
But you've cut out a lot of the complexity
of getting that React app up onto the web.
你不需要发送一个节点服务器来服务那个响应装载到你
You don't have to ship a node server to
serve that did that React mounts into you
可以只是把一些静态资产和反应将处理为您。
can just put some static assets up and
React will handle that for you.
作为一个例子，这可能看起来在一个真正的网站，这是一个旧的截图
As an example of how this might look in a
real website, this is an old screenshot of
在盖茨比的摇钱树店，用户界面已经更新，但概念是一样的。
the Gatsby's Swag Store, the UI has been
updated but the concepts are the same.
当你加载这个网站的时候,
How this works is that
when you load this site,
你看到的是来自多个来源的数据。
you're looking at data
from multiple sources.
所以第一个来源是 Shopify
So the first source is
gonna be Shopify and
Shopify 保存这些产品的库存。
Shopify keeps inventory of
each of these products.
上面有照片价钱和尺寸,
It has the photos and
the price and the sizes,
所有你在电子商务商店里能想到的东西。
all the things that you would
expect in an e-commerce store.
然后，我们在客户端，卸载零的身份验证，并
Then, we on the client side,
load off zero for authentication, and
我们使用 Shopify 的 Buy SDK 动态加载是否或
we use Shopify's Buy SDK to
dynamically load whether or
没有存货，也没有购物车。
not a thing is in stock and
to manage a shopping cart.
然后，一旦你登录，你就可以看到你的 GitHub 数据。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Then once you're
logged in, you can see your GitHub data.
所以我们使用 GitHub 来决定你是否有资格使用折扣码。
So we use GitHub to decide whether or not
you have qualified for the discount codes.
如果你向盖茨比提出一个拉请求，你将得到一个10美元的折扣码。
If you do one pull request to Gatsby,
you get a $10 discount code.
如果你做了5次，你会得到一个25美元的折扣代码,
If you do five you get
a $25 discount code,
这是盖茨比感谢参与开源项目的一种方式。
it's kind of Gatsby's way of saying
thanks for participating in open source.
所以他们用这个来计算贡献的数量。
And so they pull this to
get the contribution count.
然后在下面，你可以看到你最近的贡献。
And then below that, you can also
see your most recent contributions.
所以这是一种很酷的使用实时数据的方式。
So it's kind of a cool
way to use live data.
但是你必须被认证才有这个权利。
But you have to be authenticated for
that right.
这一切都是动态的。
This is all dynamic.
所以它在客户端运行。
So it runs on the client side.
这是一个很好的例子，说明盖茨比不仅仅是一个静态的地点，对吗？
And this is a good example of Gatsby being
more than just like static sites, right?
它可以是动态的。
It can be dynamic.
它只是静态资产。
It's just static assets.